<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<addonCore><label>labelpoints</label><version>4.1.1</version><type>Toolbox</type><identifier>e5ab52cd-4a80-11e4-9553-005056977bd0</identifier><summary>Automatically label points in your plot given x and y values &amp; an array of labels.</summary><description>[Major update with additional features coming soon; don't forget to follow this file.]

Given vectors of x-values, y-values, and a vector of label names, lablepoints.m will automatically place all labels appropriately in the plot and output their handles. This function streamlines matlab's builtin text() function and greatly increases its flexibility.  
.
xpos = [1,2,3,4];    ypos = [1,4,1,5];     labels = {'Lancaster', 'Cincinnati', 'Sofia', 'Rochester'}
h = labelpoints (xpos, ypos, labels)
.
(optional) Choose where you want your label relative to the data point using initials of compass directions (N, S, E, W, NE, NW, SE, SW, Center).
h = labelpoints (xpos, ypos, labels, 'N')
.
(optional) Add (or subtract) extra space between data points and labels by using a buffer between 0:1
h = labelpoints (xpos, ypos, labels, 'N', 0.15)
.
(optional) Decide whether or not the axis limits should automatically adjust if a label falls out of the axis limits (0/1)
h = labelpoints (xpos, ypos, labels, 'N', 0.15, 1)
.
(optional) Let labelpoints.m identify and label only the outliers in your data.  Several outlier methods are available (see help labelpoints)
 - Identify and label outliers that are N standard deviations from the mean
 - Identify and label outliers that are greater than N times the interquartile range
 - Identify and label outliers that are inside or outside of a given bound
 - Identify and label outliers that are high residuals from a linear fit of the data.
.
(optional) Easily place texts in a list stacked downward, upward, to the left or right.
h = labelpoints (xpos, ypos, labels, 'N, 'stacked', 'down')
.
(optional) Rotate all labels 
h = labelpoints (xpos, ypos, labels, 'rotation', 45)
.
(optional) Specify the font size and color of all labels
h = labelpoints (xpos, ypos, labels, 'FontSize', 12, 'Color', 'r')
.
The help section includes many versatile examples demonstrating labeling with numbers, strings, and symbols.  This function is quite flexible as the examples show.  There are only three required inputs, 3 optional inputs, and several optional parameters to increase flexibility.  The outlier options may require stats toolbox.</description><createdBy name="Adam Danz"/><image>resources/screenshot.png</image></addonCore>
